<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The decree for tithes, to be payed in London Anno MD.LXXX.</title>
            <author>City of London (England).</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1580</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06210</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16702</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S107705</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99843401</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99843401</idno>
            <idno type="VID">8132</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06210)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 8132)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 476:02)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The decree for tithes, to be payed in London Anno MD.LXXX.</title>
                  <author>City of London (England).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[By T. East] for Gabriel Cawood,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1580]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Printer's name and publication date from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tithes --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:8132:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:8132:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <p>¶ THE <hi>DE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree for Tithes,</hi> to be payed in Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anno M.D.</hi> LXXX.</p>
            <p>Imprinted at <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don for Gabriel</hi> Cawood.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="decree">
            <pb facs="tcp:8132:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:8132:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <head>The Decree for Tithes to be payed in London.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>S touching the pai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of Tithes in the Citie of <hi>London</hi> and the Lyberties of the ſame: It is fully ordered and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>créed by the moſt reuerend Father in God <hi>Thomas</hi> Archbiſhop of <hi>Canter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury,</hi> Primate and Metropolitane of al <hi>England. Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Wriothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſley</hi> &amp; Lord Chancellour of <hi>England. William</hi> Lord, Saint <hi>Iohn</hi> preſident of the Kings Maieſties Councel, and Lord great maiſter of his highneſſe houſeholde, <hi>Ihon</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſell,</hi> Lord priuie ſeale, <hi>Edward</hi> Earle of <hi>Hert<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford,</hi> Lorde great Chamberlaine of <hi>Englande, Iohn viſcount Liſle</hi> high Admirall of <hi>England, Richard Liſter</hi> knight chief Iuſtice of <hi>Engla<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d,</hi> &amp; <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger Cholmeley</hi> knight, chief baron of his Graces Eſchequer, this preſent
<pb facs="tcp:8132:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
twentie and foure day of February, <hi>Anno Domini ſecundum curſum &amp; computationem Eccleſiae Angelicanae milleſimo quinge<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>teſimo quadrageſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mo quinto,</hi> according to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſtatute in ſuch caſe lately prouided, That the Citizens and inhabitants of the ſaid Citie of <hi>London</hi> and liberties of the ſame, for the time being, ſhall yeare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly w<hi rend="sup">t</hi>hout fraud or couin for euer pay their tithes to the Parſons, Vicars, and Curates of the ſayd Citie &amp; their ſucceſſours for the time béeing, after the rate héereafter following, that is to wit, of euery ten ſhillings rent by yeare of all and euery houſe &amp; hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, ſhoppes, warehouſes, cellers, and ſtables, and euery of them, within the ſayde Citie and liberties of the ſame .xvi. pence halfe peny. And of euery twentie ſhillings rent by yere of all and euerye ſuch houſe &amp; houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, cellars and ſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, &amp; euery of them, within the ſaid Citie and liberties, two ſhillings and nine pence: And ſo aboue the rent of xx.s. by yeare, aſcending from .x.s.
<pb facs="tcp:8132:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 19 -->
to x.s. according to the rate afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſayd.</p>
            <p>Item y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> wher any leaſe is or ſhall be made of anye dwellyng houſe or houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, cellars, or ſtables, or of any of them, by fraud or couin, reſeruing leſſe rent then hath ben accuſtomed, or is or that any ſuch leaſe ſhalbe made without anye rent reſerued vpon the ſame, by reaſon of any fine or income payd before hand, or by any other frand or couin: That then in euery ſuch caſe the tenaunt or fermour, tenaunts or fermoures therof, ſhal pay for his or their tithes of the ſame, after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate aforeſaid, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the quantitie of ſuch rent or rents, as y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame houſe or houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, celars or ſtables, or any of them were laſt letten for, without fraude or couin before the making of ſuch leaſe.</p>
            <p>Item that euery owner or owners, inheritor or inheritors, of any dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyng houſe or houſes, ſhops, ware<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſes, cellers, or ſtables, or anye of them within the ſaid citie &amp; liberties,
<pb facs="tcp:8132:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
inhabiting or occupying y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe or themſelues, ſhall paye after ſuch rate of tithe as is aboueſayde, after the quantitie of ſuch yearelye rent, as the ſame was laſt letten for, without fraud or couin.</p>
            <p>Item if any perſon or perſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s haue taken or héerafter ſhal take any meſe or manſion place by leaſe, &amp; the taker or takers theroff his or their execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors or aſſignes doth or ſhal inhabite in part theroff, &amp; haue or hath w<hi rend="sup">t</hi>in viii. yeares laſt paſt before this order or héereafter wil or ſhall let out the reſidue of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame: That then in ſuch caſe, y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> principal fermour or fermors or firſt taker or takers therof, his or their executours or aſſignes, ſhal pay his or their tithes after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſayd, according to his or their quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titie therin, &amp; that his or their execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors aſſigne or aſſignes, ſhal pay his or their tithes after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate aboueſaid, according to the quantitie of his or their rent by yeare.</p>
            <p>And y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> if any perſon or perſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s, haue or ſhall take diuers manſion houſes,
<pb facs="tcp:8132:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 20 -->
ſhops, warehouſes, cellers, or ſtables in one leaſe, &amp; letteth or ſhall let out one or more of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſaid houſes &amp; kepeth or ſhall kéepe one or more in his or their owne hands, &amp; inhabiteth or in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habiten in the ſame: That then the ſaid taker or takers, &amp; his or their ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecutors or aſſignes, ſhall pay his or their tithes after the rate aboueſaid, according to the quantitie of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> yere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly rent of ſuch manſion houſe or hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes reteyned in his or their handes. And that his aſſigne or aſſignes of the reſidue of the ſaid manſion houſe or houſes ſhal pay his or their yerely tithes after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate aboueſaid, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> qua<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>titie of their yerely re<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts. Ite<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> if ſuch fermour or fermours, or his or their aſſignes of any manſion houſes, warehouſes, ſhops, cellers, or ſtables, hath at any time within eight yeares laſt paſt, or ſhall héereafter let ouer all the ſayd manſion houſe or houſes conteyned in his or theyr leaſe to one perſon or to diuers per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons: That then the inhabitauntes leaſes or occupiers of them, and of
<pb facs="tcp:8132:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
euery of them ſhall pay their tithes, after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate of ſuch rents as the ſayd inhabitaunts, leaſes, or occupiers, and their aſſigne or aſſignes, ben or ſhal be charged withall, without fraud or co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uin.</p>
            <p>Item if any dwelling houſe with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in eight yeares laſt paſt was or héere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall be conuerted into a ware<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe, Forehouſe, or ſuch lyke, or if a warehouſe, ſtorehouſe, or ſuch like w<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid eight yeares, was or heere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhalbe co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>uerted into a dwelling houſe: That the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the occupier or occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piers thereoff ſhall pay tithes for the ſame after the rate aboue declared of manſion houſe rents.</p>
            <p>Item that where any perſon ſhall demiſe any Diehouſe or Brewhouſe with implementes conuenient and neceſſary for dying or brewing, reſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing a rent vpon the ſame, as well in reſpect of ſuch implements as in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of ſuch Diehouſe or Brewhouſe. That then the tenaunt ſhall paye his tithes, after ſuch rate as is aboueſaid, the third penie abated. And that euery
<pb facs="tcp:8132:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 21 -->
principall houſe or houſes with key or wharfe, hauing any Crane or gibet belo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ging to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame, ſhal pay after like rate of their rents as is aforeſaid the third penny abated. And that other wharfes belonging to houſes, hauing no Crane or gibet, ſhall pay for theyr tithes as ſhalbe paid for manſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes in forme aforeſayd.</p>
            <p>Item that where any manſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> houſe w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> a ſhop, ſtable, warehouſes, wharfe, with Crane, timberyard, teinteryard, or garden belonging to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame, or as parcel of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame, is or ſhalbe occupied together, y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> if the ſame be héereafter ſeuered or deuided, or at any time w<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in .viij. years laſt paſt were ſeuered or deuided: That the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the farmour or far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, occupier, or occupiers theroff ſhal pay ſuch tithes as aboueſayd for ſuch ſhops, ſtable, ware-houſe, wharfe with Crane, timberyard, teinteryard, or garden aforeſaid ſo ſeuered or deui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate of their ſeueral rentes therevpon reſerued.</p>
            <p>Item that the ſayde citezens &amp; in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitantes ſhall paye their tythes
<pb facs="tcp:8132:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 22 -->
quarterly, that is to ſay, at the feaſt of Eaſter, the Natiuitie of S. <hi>Iohn Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſt,</hi> the feaſt of S. <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>angell, and the natiuitie of our Lorde by euen portions.</p>
            <p>Item that euery houſeholder pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ten ſhillinges rent or aboue, ſhall for him or hir ſelfe be diſcharged of theyr foure offeringe dayes: but his wyfe, children, ſeruaunt or others of theyr family, taking theyr rightes of the Church at Eaſter, ſhall paye two pence for theyr foure offeringe dayes yéerely.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, and it is decrée<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that if any houſe or houſes, which hath ben or héereafter ſhalbe letten for x. ſhillings rent by yeare or more, bée or hath at anye time within eyght yeares laſt paſſed, or héereafter ſhalbée deuided and leaſſed into ſmall parcels or members, yelding leſſe yéerely rent then x. ſhillings by yeare: That then the owner or owners, if he or they dwell in any part of ſuch houſe, or els the principal leaſe or leaſes, if the ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner or owners doe not dwell in ſome
<pb facs="tcp:8132:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 22 -->
part of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame, ſhal fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> hencefoorth pay for his or their tithes, after ſuch rate of rent as the ſame houſe was accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed to be letten for before ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uiſion or deuiding into parts or mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers. And y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> vnder farmour and far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, leaſe and leaſes, to be diſchar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged of all tithes, for ſuche ſmall parcels, parts or members rented at leſſe yearely rents then x. ſhillings by yeare, without fraud or couin, paying two pence a péece yearely for their .iiij offering dayes.</p>
            <p>Prouided alway, &amp; it is decréede, that for ſuch gardens as apperteyne not to any manſion houſe, and which any perſon or perſons, holdeth or ſhal holde in his or their handes for plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, or to his owne vſe, that then the perſon ſo holding the ſame ſhall paye no tithes for the ſame. But if any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons, which holdeth and ſhal holde any ſuch garden, conteininge halfe an Acre or more, doth or ſhall make any yéerely profite thereoff by way of ſale: that then he or they ſhall paye tithes for the ſame, after ſuche
<pb facs="tcp:8132:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 23 -->
rate of his rent, as is héerein firſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue ſpecified.</p>
            <p>Prouided alſo that if any ſuch gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens now béeing of the quantitie of halfe an Acre or more, bée héereafter by fraude or couin deuided into any leſſe quantitie or quantities, then to pay tith, according to the rate aboue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſayde.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaye that this decrée ſhall not extend to the houſes of great men, or noble men, or noble women, kept in theyr owne handes, and not letten for any rent, which in time paſt hath payed no tithes, ſo long as they ſhall ſo continue vnletten, nor to any halls of craftes or companies ſo long as they be kepte vnletten, ſo that the ſame halls in time paſt haue not vſed to pay any tithes.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, &amp; it is decréed, that this preſent order and decrée ſhal not in anye wiſe extende to binde or charge any ſheddes, ſtables, cellers, timber yardes, ne teynter yardes, which wer neuer parcel of any dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling houſe, ne apperteining or belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb facs="tcp:8132:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 23 -->
to any dwellinge houſe, ne haue accuſtomed to paye any tithes: but y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> the ſayd Citizens &amp; inhabitants ſhall thereoff be quiet of payment, of any tithes, as it hath ben vſed and accuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med.</p>
            <p>Prouided alſo, and it is decréede, that where leſſe ſumme thou after the rate of ſixtéene pence half penny in the tenne ſhillinges rent, or leſſe ſumme then two ſhillinges and nine pence in the twentie ſhillinges rente, hath ben accuſtomed to be payde for tithes, that then in ſuch places, the ſayde Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tizens and inhabitantes ſhall pay but onely after ſuch rate as hath bene ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed.</p>
            <p>Item, it is alſo decréede, y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> if any va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ryaunce, controuerſie, or ſtriefe do or ſhall héereafter aryſe in the ſayd Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie for no payment of any tithes: or if any variaunce or doubt ariſe vpon the true knowledge or diuiſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> of any rent or tithes within the liberties of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſaid citie, or of any extent or aſſemblant thereoff, or if any doubt riſe vpon any other thing conteined within this de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crée:
<pb facs="tcp:8132:8"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 24 -->
that then vppon complaint made by the partie gréeued to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Mayre of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> citie of <hi>London</hi> for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> time being, the ſayd Mayre by the aduiſe of counſaile ſhall call the ſayd parties before him, &amp; make a finall ende in the ſame, with coſts to be rewarded at the diſcreati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the ſayd Mayre &amp; his aſſiſtants, according to the intent &amp; purpoſe of this preſent decrée.</p>
            <p>And if y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> the ſayd Mayre make not an ende thereoff within two moneths af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter complaynte to him made, or if any of the ſayde parties finde themſelues grieued: That then the Lord Chaun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellour of England for the time being vpon complainte to him made within thrée monethes then next following. ſhall make an ende of the ſame, with ſuch coſtes to be rewarded as ſhalbe thought conuenient, according to the intent and purporſe of this ſaid decrée.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, that if any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons take any tenement for a leſſe rent then was accuſtomed to be letten for, by reaſon of any greate ruine and decay, burning, or ſuch lyke
<pb facs="tcp:8132:8"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 24 -->
occaſions or miſfortunes: That then ſuch perſon or perſons, his executors or aſſignes ſhal pay tithes onely after the rate of the rent reſerued in his or their leaſe, &amp; none otherwiſe, as long as the ſame leaſe ſhall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dure.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>¶ Imprinted at London</hi> by Thomas Eaſt, for Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>briell Cawood. 1580.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
